Guide to the Robert Wilson papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Robert Wilson Papers,
1969-1995.
Wilson, Robert, 1941-
148 linear ft. (ca. 149,000 items in 292 boxes; 1 phonodisc; 1 audio cassette; 15 oversize folders; 3 scrapbooks; 108 posters)
Columbia University, Rare Book and Manuscripts Library, Butler Library, New York, NY 10027.
4079713
Biographical Note
American dramatist, director, designer, performer, writer and artist.
Scope and Content
Correspondence, outlines, scripts, production notes, technical materials, story boards, contracts, posters, programs, announcements, recordings, reviews, and other printed materials relating to all aspects of Robert Wilson's theater works, opera, films, artwork and video productions. There are files for all of Wilson's theatrical performances, the most extensive of which is the CIVIL warS. Also included are the files of the Byrd Hoffman Foundation.
Series II contains press materials for 1988 and research materials for King Lear, The Forest, and Parsifal, as well as miscellaneous research files for 1987. In addition, one can find various documents (letters, contracts, etc.) relating to the following productions: The Forest; Alcestis; The Golden Windows; Patio; Edison; Black Rider; Murder (Deafman Glance); CIVIL warS; and Knee Plays. A group of miscellaneous files follows, containing such items as scores, research materials, and budget documentation. In the oversize folders of the series are scores for The Golden Windows and De Materie, research for Black Rider, a press kit for Knee Plays, and various King Lear documents.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into 3 series:
Series I
Series II
Series III
Subjects
Byrd Hoffman Foundation.; Experimental theater.; Postmodernism.; Theater--Production and direction.; Theatrical producers and directors.; Dramatists.; Posters.; Playbills.; Contracts; Announcements.; Clippings.; Scripts.; Scrapbooks.; Reviews.; Manuscripts (literary).
Access Restrictions
Series II, Box 20: Permission of the Byrd Hoffman Foundation required.
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material from the Rare Book and Manuscript Library at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
Acquisition
Papers Wilson, Robert and the Byrd Hoffman Foundation Gift
Gift of Robert Wilson and the Byrd Hoffman Foundation, 1988-1991.
- Series I
  - Subseries I.1: Cataloged Correspondence
    Herein are filed materials relating to Byrd Hoffman Foundation activities, Robert Wilson in general, and the works of his Associates. Also included in this section are materials related to lectures and other public appearances unrelated to performance. Also included here are files related to suspended projects and works not completed. For works related to productions see the alphabetical list of productions. There are separate files of materials related to videos produced as independent works and to exhibitions of his artistic works. PRODUCTION FILES (Boxes 24-185). Herein are files related to specific productions. Also included are materials related to videos of those productions or videos of the same title. Videos that were produced only as vodeos are liste under Videos. Press materials about productions may be found either with the production files and/or in the Press files. The "Press files" are arranged chronologically for each production. Printed materials and press materials that were not excerpted from the journals in which they appear are filed after "Press." Materials related to suspended projects and works not completed can be found among the General Files. VIDEOS (Boxes 186-197). Herein are filed papers relating to video projects that were independent of theatrical productions.
    See also Flat for scrapbook of photocopies of correspondence and conversations between R. Wilson and Dallas Pratt
    - Ashley, George
    - Bolcom, William
    - Glass, Philip
    - Ionesco, Eugene
    - Johns, Jasper
    - Norman, Jessye
    - Pesle, Benedicte
    - Pratt, Dallas
    - Wilson, Mr. & Mrs. D. M.
  - Subseries I.2: Arranged Correspondence
    - Andriga, Mel (Box 1)
    - Andrews, Raymond (Box 1)
    - Bando, Tamasaburo (Box 1)
    - Bandy, C. Mary Lee (Box 1)
    - Brecht, Stefan (Box 1)
    - Bridge, Marissa (Box 1)
    - Eggert, Mara (Box 1)
    - Farrel, Florence (Box 1)
    - Forte, Simone (Box 1)
    - Gilbert, Jessie Dunn (Box 1)
    - Johnston, Jill (Box 1)
    - King, Kenneth (Box 1)
    - Kondrat, Hope (Box 1)
    - Marijen, Franz (Box 1)
    - McEntire, Joanne (Box 1)
    - Parr, Ted (Box 1)
    - Ray, Gordon (Box 1)
    - Stokes, Eric (Box 1)
    - Watson, Steve (Box 1)
    - Zocher, Gerti (Box 1)
  - Subseries I.3: General Files
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence
      - Byrd Hoffman Foundation Correspondence, [n.p.], 1973-1984 (Box 2)
      - Byrd Hoffman Foundation Correspondence, [n.p.], 1985-1986 (Box 3)
      - Byrd Hoffman Foundation Correspondence, [n.p.], June 1986-1988 (Box 4)
      - Byrd Hoffman Foundation Miscellaneous Correspondence, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 5)
      - Artservice Correspondence, [n.p.], 1976-1979, 1984 (Box 5)
      - Artservice Correspondence with Benedicte Pestle, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 5)
      - Artservice Financial records, [n.p.], 1980-1982 (Box 5)
      - Newsletter, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 5)
      - Miscellaneous: By-laws, Lease, Contract with Benedicte Pestle, Miscellaneous, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 5)
      - Byrd Hoffman Foundation Financial -- --Fund Raising, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 6)
      - Byrd Hoffman Foundation Financial -- --Fund Raising, NEA, 1973-1984 (Box 7)
      - Byrd Hoffman Foundation Financial -- --Fund Raising, Rockefeller Foundation, 1977-1983 (Box 8)
      - Financial -- --Fund Raising, New York State. Council on the Arts, 1980-1985 (Box 8)
      - Byrd Hoffman School of Byrds Correspondence -- --Photomontage by Scotty Snyder, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 9)
      - Byrd Hoffman School of Byrds Activities (includes early Wilson activities), [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 10)
      - Byrd Hoffman School of Byrds Activities, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 11)
      - Byrd Hoffman School of Byrds Activities, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 12)
      - Byrd Hoffman School of Byrds Associates, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 13)
      - Robert Wilson Resumes and Bios, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 14)
      - Robert Wilson Lectures, Workshops, Conferences, & Public Appearances, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 14)
        [See also School of Byrds--Activities]
      - Robert Wilson Interviews, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 15)
      - Robert Wilson Books file, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 16)
        [Materials concerning books and articles about Wilson including typescripts of articles, proofs, etc.]
      - Robert Wilson Books file, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 17)
      - Robert Wilson Books file -- Mechanicals for Theatre of Images, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 18)
      - Robert Wilson Address Books and Contacts -- Calendars and Itineraries, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 19)
      - Robert Wilson Calendars, Itineraries and Schedules, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 20)
      - Robert Wilson Suspended projects, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 21)
      - Robert Wilson Suspended projects, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 22)
      - Robert Wilson Works not completed: -- --New play X -- --New play ideas, Summer 1978 -- --Radio Play (First version of Civil Wars, 1980) (Artservice) -- --Konrad Henkel (Box 23)
  - Subseries I.4: Production Files
    - Alcestis
      - General: Boston, ART, Boston, 1986 (Box 24)
      - Festival D' Automne,1986 -- Stuttgart, 1987 -- Delphi -- Barcelona, [v.p.], [1986/87] (Box 24)
      - Printed Script, Stuttgart, 1986/7 (Box 25)
      - Printed Script (Box 25)
    - Byrdwoman
      - Materials relating to Byrdwoman (Box 26)
    - The CIVIL warS
      The CIVIL warS Administrative files include correspondence and other materials related to technical matters, production details, printed materials, etc beyond contracts and budgetary files. Users should also note that an attempt has been made to group the materials by production, but this has not always been possible becouse of problems of identification and some attempt has been made to preserve the integrity of the arrangement of the materials as they were at the Byrd Hoffman Foundation and at Art Service International.
      - Administrative files -- Correspondence, contracts, budgets, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 27)
      - Administrative files -- Correspondence, contracts, budgets, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 28)
      - Administrative files: -- Correspondence, contracts, budgets-ArtService International Files, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 29)
      - Administrative files: Correspondence, contracts, budgets, Los Angeles, [n.d.] (Box 30)
      - Administrative files: Correspondence, contracts, budgets, Los Angeles, [n.d.] (Box 31)
      - Administrative file: Correspondence, contracts, budgets, Los Angeles, [n.d.] (Box 32A)
      - Administrative files: Correspondence, contracts, budgets, Los Angeles, [n.d.] (Box 32B)
      - Administrative files: Correspondence, contracts, budgets, Netherlands, [n.d.] (Box 33)
      - Administrative files: Correspondence, contracts, budgets -- General, Netherlands, [n.d.] (Box 34)
      - Administrative files: Correspondence, contracts, budgets, Netherlands & France Tour, [n.d.] (Box 35)
      - Administrative files: Correspondence, contracts, budgets, Netherlands/France Tour, [n.d.] (Box 36)
      - General, Netherlands/France Tour, [n.d.] (Box 37)
      - Administrative files: Correspondence, contracts, budgets, France, [n.d.] (Box 38)
      - Administrative files: Artservice, France, [n.d.] (Box 39)
      - Administrative files: -- Frieburg, Germany--Workshop--Administrative files -- Germany; Munich--Administrative files, Germany, 1982 (Box 40)
        [See Flat]
      - Administrative files, Germany, [n.d.] (Box 41)
      - Administrative files, Japan, [n.d.] (Box 42)
      - Administrative files, Japan, [n.d.] (Box 43)
      - Administrative files: BAM production -- Rome -- Other productions, [v.p.], [n.d.] (Box 44)
      - Marc Dondey -- Administrative files, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 45)
      - Marc Dondey -- Administrative files, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 46)
      - General, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 47)
      - General -- Composers book, [n.p. ], [n.d.] (Box 48)
      - Research, [n.p. ], [n.d.] (Box 49)
      - Research, [n.p. ], [n.d.] (Box 50)
      - Research--Berlin Nationalgalerie, Berlin, [n.d.] (Box 51)
      - Research, Japan, [n.d.] (Box 52)
      - Storyboards and Visual Research -- Original dialog, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 53)
      - Preliminary Scripts, Scripts, Translations, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 54)
        [See also General Files--Works Not Completed]
      - Scripts, Outlines, Storyboards, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 55)
      - Scripts, Outlines, Storyboards, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 56)
      - Freiburg scripts, Freiburg, [n.d.] (Box 57)
      - Scripts, Scores, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 58)
      - Scripts, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 59)
      - Scripts, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 60A)
      - Scripts, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 60B)
      - Scripts, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 60C)
      - Scripts, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 60D)
        [See also Printed for Printed Scripts]
      - Production proposals, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 61)
      - Production books Act IA-C, IIA-IIC, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 62)
      - Production books Act IIIA-E, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 63)
      - Production books Act IVA Holland, IVA Germany, IVA France,IVA -- USA, IVA Japan -- Holland/Germany/France/Japan, [v.p.], [n.d.] (Box 64)
      - Production books Act VA-C, IIA-B France, IIIA-B France -- Knee Plays, France, [n.d.] (Box 65)
      - Contact Books, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 66)
      - Technical, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 67)
      - Knee Plays, Administrative, General, Technical, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 68)
      - Knee Plays, Administrative, General, Technical, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 69)
      - Knee Plays-- -- European Tour,1985 -- Knee Plays--ART,1985 -- Knee Plays--IPA Tour,1986 -- Knee Plays--IPA Tour,1988 -- Knee Plays--Press, [v.p.], [n.d.] (Box 70)
      - Production, Texas, 1986 (Box 71)
      - Production, Texas, 1986 (Box 72)
      - Production, Texas, 1986 (Box 73)
      - Video -- Miscellaneous, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 74)
      - Press Packets -- Press, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 75)
        [See also Oversize]
      - Printed--Flyers, programs, announcements, etc. [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 76)
      - Printed Script--Photocopy--Kšln Section (Act IA, IIIE, IV) -- Printed Script--Photocopy--Rome Section (Act V) -- Printed Script--Photocopy--(Act I Scene B), [v.p.], [n.d.] (Box 77)
      - Printed -- --Knee Plays--Printed, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 78)
      - Printed -- --Miscellaneous, Magazines, etc. [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 79)
        [Note: See also Oversize]
      - Cosmopolitan Greetings -- Program Book, etc., [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 80)
    - Deafman Glance
      For Program Prologue: Now: Overture for A Deafman, Prologue to the Fourth Act of Deafman Glance, and Overture to the Fourth Act of Deafman Glance see Program Prologue
      - Note: General -- Iowa -- BAM -- European Tour, [v.p.], [n.d.] (Box 81)
      - Video -- Press, [n.p.], 1982 (Box 82A)
      - Press, (Artservice) -- Press, [n.p.], 1978 (Box 82B)
        [ See also Oversize]
    - Death Destruction and Detroit
      - Correspondence -- Contracts -- General, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 83)
      - Music, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 84)
      - Research, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 85)
      - Scripts, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 86)
      - Scripts, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 87)
      - Storyboards, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 88)
      - Technical, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 89)
      - Miscellaneous -- Press, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 90)
      - Printed Script, 1979 & Photocopy -- Printed, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 91)
      - Correspondence -- General -- Research, [n.p.], 1985, 1986, 1987 (Box 92)
      - Scripts--English text, notes, deletions -- Script labelled Scene 14 -- Scripts from workshop -- Scripts and notes for development, July 24, 1985 -- Script--Master copy, July 31, 1985, [n.p.], [v.d.] (Box 93)
      - Script for Workshop Nov.- Dec. 1985 -- Program Book-SchaubŸhne am Lehineiner, 1987 -- Printed, [n.p.], 1985, 1987 (Box 94)
    - Dia/Log
      - Administrative -- Programs, Flyers -- Press -- Dia/Log (with Lucinda Child, Christopher Knowles, Robert Wilson) -- Program, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 95)
    - Dialog/Curious George
      - AdministrativeAdministrative (Artservice), [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 96)
      - Production (Artservice) -- Production N.B. Some labelled Dialog Five -- Drawings for slides, writings by Christopher Knowles, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 97)
      - Scripts N.B. Some labelled Dialog Five -- Scripts (Artservice), [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 98)
      - Storyboards and television scripts, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 99)
      - Programs -- Press, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 100)
    - Dialog/Network
      - Administrative -- Scripts -- Technical -- Programs -- Flyers, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 101)
    - $ Value of Man
      - Administrative -- Research, Textual ideas, Transcriptions from notebooks, -- Workshop notes -- Scripts and printed scripts -- Technical--notes, scripts, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 102)
      - Program and book notes -- Programs, flyers, announcements -- Press -- Printed, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 103)
    - Edison
      - Administrative, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 104)
      - Administrative (Artservice), [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 105)
      - Administrative -- Research -- Research (Artservice) -- Technical, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 106)
      - Scripts, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 107)
      - Scripts, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 108A)
      - Scripts, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 108B)
      - Production -- Production Book -- Production Book [2], [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 109)
      - Production Book [3] -- Programs, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 110)
      - Press (Artservice), [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 111)
      - Press, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 112)
    - Einstein on the Beach
      - Administrative--Budget and financial -- Administrative--Contracts, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 113)
      - Administrative--Miscellaneous, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 114)
      - Administrative--Tour, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 115)
      - Administrative--Tour (Artservice) -- Administrative--Publications (Artservice) -- Administrative--Publications, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 116)
      - Administrative--Brooklyn Academy of Music -- Administrative--Metropolitan Opera -- Administrative--Documentary, film, video, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 117)
      - Research -- Scripts and notes -- Printed script -- Production, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 118)
      - Technical--Correspondence -- Technical, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 119)
      - Programs, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 120)
      - Press--Miscellaneous administrative -- Press--Packets, etc. [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 121)
      - Press, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 122)
      - Press, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 123)
      - Press, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 124)
      - Printed, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 125)
    - Faustus
      - Research -- Printed, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 126)
    - The Forest
      - Proposals -- Film Proposals, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 127)
      - Research, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 128)
      - Research -- Research--Notes -- Scripts, scenario, printed script -- Production--Photocopies of drawings -- Production--Notes, drawings, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 129)
      - Miscellaneous: Tickets, Programs, Press releases -- Press (see Flat) -- Printed (see Oversize), [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 130)
    - Four Saints in Three Acts
      - Administrative -- Administrative (Artservice) -- Research -- Scripts, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 131)
    - The Golden Windows
      - Administrative -- Administrative (France, 1986)--Suspended -- Research, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 132)
      - Scripts, Printed Script, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 133)
      - Sketches, Rehearsal notes, Technical notes -- Technical -- Programs, Announcements, Flyers, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 134)
      - Press -- Printed, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 135)
    - Great Day in the Morning
      - Administrative (Artservice) -- Administrative, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 136)
      - Research -- Notes and Synopses -- Technical, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 137)
      - Programs, Flyers -- Press -- Printed, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 138)
    - Hamletmachine
      - New York University production -- Thalia Theatre, Hamburg, production -- Almeida Theatre tour production, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 139)
      - Almeida Theatre tour -- Theatre plans (blueprints) -- Text -- Technical and production notes--Master file -- Miscellaneous -- Programs and Flyers -- Press -- Printed, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 140)
      - Handbill, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 141)
    - I Was Sitting on My Patio This Guy Appeared I Thought I Was Halucinating
      - Administrative, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 142)
      - Film and Video -- Scripts, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 142)
      - Scripts -- Storyboards, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 144)
      - Technical -- Programs and Flyers, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 145)
      - Press releases, packets etc. -- Press, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 146)
      - Press (see also Flat) -- Printed, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 147)
    - Ka Mountain
      - Administrative -- Writing, notebooks and notes (5 notebooks containing Wilson's writings & sketches for Ka Mt. & Overture) -- Transcript of tape with Wilson, Carol Mullins, Cindy Lubar, etc. 12/21/74 & other writings and drawings -- Ann Wilson's Notes, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 148)
      - Technical and Production -- Newsletters, Programs & Flyers -- Press, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 149)
      - Printed, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 150)
    - King Lear
      - Administrative, Production -- Research -- Printed, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 151)
    - King of Spain
      - Administrative -- Film -- Writings about Production: Production Notes; In complete typescript of projected book including some material on Stalin (See also Life and Times of Sigmund Freud--Book File); Printed version of "Production notes.. ." in New American Plays, v. 3, 1970; Dallas Pratt article "Among the archtypes" -- Photograph -- Programs and flyers -- Press release and press, [n.p.], [v.d.] (Box 152)
    - A Letter for Queen Victoria
      - Administrative -- Administrative--Contracts, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 153)
      - Administrative--Tour -- Administrative--Vides and recording -- Bonnie Marrance book -- Research & design, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 154)
      - Scripts and writings, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 155)
      - Technical Scripts -- Technical, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 156)
      - Production -- Production--Photographs -- Production--Writings about Q.V. by production members -- Programs, flyers, announcements, etc. [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 157)
      - Press -- Printed, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 158)
    - Life and Times of Dave Clark
      - Administrative -- Scripts, script inserts, text fragments, performance -- schedule, outline -- Technical -- Programs -- Press, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 159)
      - Life and Time of Joseph Stalin -- Administrative, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 160)
      - Life and Times of Joseph Stalin -- Life and Times of Joseph Stalin -- Administrative -- Research and Chair drawings -- Projected book -- Scripts -- Recording of Stalin (see Flat), [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 161)
      - Life and Times of Joseph Stalin -- Life and Times of Joseph Stalin -- Technical -- Technical script -- Costume sketches, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 162)
      - Life and Times of Joseph Stalin -- Life and Times of Joseph Stalin -- Technical -- Inventories -- Production notes & cast information -- Writings about Stalin -- (See also Life and Times of Sigmund Freud Book File) -- Program materials -- Programs -- Press releases & ads, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 163)
      - Life and Times of Joseph Stalin -- Press -- Printed, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 164)
      - Life and Times of Sigmund Freud -- Administrative -- Book file: Administrative; Text for projected book--Wilson's notes on Freud, etc (August 1971 to September 1971, June 1973) -- Introductory speech and manuscript notes -- Technical -- Production Writings and drawings related to the production -- by members of the group -- -- Program notes, programs and flyers, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 165)
      - Life and Times of Sigmund Freud -- Press releases, quotes, ad -- Press -- Printed, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 166)
      - A Mad Man A Mad Giant A Mad Dog A Mad Urge A Mad Face -- Administrative, Production and Technical -- Programs -- Press -- Printed, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 167)
      - A Man in the Raincoat--I -- Administrative -- Research -- Scripts and printed scripts -- Technical -- Press, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 168)
      - A Man in the Raincoat-II -- Administrative -- Scripts -- Material prepared for Rob Malasch 9/18/86 (Scripts, scripts with technical notes, etc.) -- Technical -- Programs -- Printed, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 169)
      - Le Martyre de Saint-Sebastien -- Research and design -- Programs -- Press -- Printed, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 170)
      - Medea -- Correspondence and Administrative files -- Correspondence R. Wilson-G. Bryars -- Contracts, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 171)
      - Medea -- Research, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 172)
      - Medea -- Research and notes -- Research--scripts -- Dramaturg's notebook, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 173)
      - Medea -- Synopsis, Description and Scripts, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 174)
      - Medea -- Music--G. Bryar's notes, technical, scores, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 175)
      - Medea -- Technical--Marked scripts, technical scripts, lights, sets, props, etc. -- Technical--Costumes, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 176)
      - Medea -- Production--Cast, Schedules -- Program notes -- Press -- Printed, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 177)
      - Overture (Ka Mountain) -- Administrative -- Writings, lists, sketches, letters, descriptions, notebook -- with sketches -- Note: See also Ka Mountain, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 178)
      - Overture (Ka Mountain) -- Programs (see also Flat) -- Press -- Note: Overture to the Fourth Act of Deafman Glance see -- Program Prologue, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 179)